We've seen how to setup a breakpoint and use media queries to
我们已经知道了如何设置不同的媒体查询断点
create different layouts for smaller screens and larger screens.
来针对小屏幕和大屏幕创建不同的布局样式
But there are some development moments that will call for three possible layouts.
但是在一些情况下 我们可能需要 3 种不同的布局方式
A simple example would be creating two different breakpoints to set it up,
一个简单的例子是创建 2 个不同的断点
so that X, we'll call the first set of CSS rules,
比如 X 是我们的第一套 CSS 样式
X rules apply at the beginning,
X 样式放置在最开始
let's say between zero pixels and 900 pixels,
针对 0 到 900 像素的情况
and then we'll set a breakpoint at 900,
然后我们在 900 设置一个断点
and so Y set of rules apply between 900 and let's say 1150 pixels.
样式 Y 用于 900 到 1150 像素之间情况
Then anything above 1150 pixels will be set of rules Z,
然后所有大于 1150 像素的情况则叫做样式 Z
which will have its own set of rules.
也拥有一套独立的样式
You could really set up as many media breakpoints as you want but the truth is,
你可以添加任意数量的断点 只要你喜欢
they start to conflict pretty quickly.
但是它们可能很快会产生冲突
So let's start at two and see if we can get by with that.
所以我们还是先试着从 2 个断点开始
So back to the code that we've been looking at,
回到我们的代码中
you can see that we have set up mobile first.
我们采用了移动端优先的方式
What we want our grid template areas to look like,
在 grid-template-areas 中
at the least wide really screen size.
我们想要在小屏幕情况下内容尽可能的宽一些
So in that instance,
所以这里
we just want one column with all of our content start.
我们给所有的内容都设置成了一列的方式
Now, if we come down here,
然后在下面
we see I've set up a media query for what I'm calling medium screens.
我们针对中型屏幕设置了对应的媒体查询样式
Medium screens I'm saying,
这里的中型屏幕是指
are between a minimum width of 600 pixels,
介于 600 像素
and now this is new for us a max width of 1100 pixels.
到 1100 像素之间宽度的屏幕
Max-width works the same way as min-width,
max-width 和 min-width 的工作方式一样
it sets a boundary.
用于设置断点的边界
So what this means is that,
所以这里的意思是
the min-width of this it's going to have to be 601 pixels,
最小宽度为 601 像素
and it can't be more than 1100 pixels.
最大宽度不超过 1100 像素
So everything in between this range will reflect
所有在这个范围内的屏幕
this grid template area which includes an aquamarine border.
都会采用这个 grid-template-areas 的样式 同时会有一个海蓝色的边框
So let's take a look at that switch first.
我们来看看变化情况
If we come over into the browser,
在浏览器中
we can see that we have our column structure here in our tiny screen.
因为是在小屏幕上 我们可以看到所有内容呈一列排序
Once I get it out to 600 pixels,
而一旦我们将屏幕拉到 600 像素后
you can see that it creates a two column structure here.
你可以看到它显示出了 2 列结构
So this will take me all the way to 1100 pixels.
这种样式会一直应用到 1100 像素为止
But now, I've sent an additional rule for large screens
但是现在 我们也设置了针对大屏幕的额外样式
that says I want it to be setup where the sidebar has more room,
这种情况下我们的 siderbar 会占有更多的空间
right here between 600 and 1100.
在 600 到 1100 像素之间
Outside bars just going to take up two of these columns.
sidebar 只占据了 2 列的空间
But we're saying on a large enough screen,
而在大屏幕情况下
we actually want our sidebar to come out and take up four columns.
我们希望 sidebar 占据 4 列空间
So if we continue now to bring this across,
如果我们继续拖动屏幕的话
boom did you see that?
看见了没？
So all the way across here we can see it has a layout that has three rows,
这里我们可以看到有 3 行布局
with two columns in the middle row with plenty of room for the blog posts,
在中间的一行中会有 2 列  blog post 占据了很多的空间
maybe too much one could argue.
可能稍微有点过于大了
Then as you come in and the room shrinks,
随着你缩小屏幕
these things are going to take up more even space,
右边的区域会重新占据更多的空间
but that as we get smaller,
随着屏幕继续变得更小
you can see it I'll just take up one column.
你可以看见它们都回到了一列的情况
This is an example of how you can use multiple breakpoints to
好了 这就是如何在 CSS grid 中
set up multiple views using CSS grid.
使用多个媒体查询断点的例子了